in this lesson we'll be going over how
在这一课中，我们将复习如何
to use mesh gradients which is in my
使用我的中的网格渐变
opinion the most advanced feature in
认为中最先进的功能
inkscape so if you can get the hang of
如果你能掌握Inkscape的诀窍
how to use this then you should be
如何使用这个，那么你就应该
pretty Limitless with the rest of the
与其他人相比，这是相当无限的
software before we get started though I
在我们开始之前的软件，虽然我
would recommend that you save your
我会建议你把你的
document and get in the habit of
记录并养成……的习惯
pressing Ctrl s every few steps because
每隔几步按一次Ctrl键S，因为
this tool can be a little glitchy at
此工具在以下方面可能有点小问题
times and you may experience some
时间，你可能会经历一些
crashing so it would be good to save
崩溃了，所以救了它会很好
your work so that you don't lose your
你的工作，这样你就不会失去你的
progress
进展
so to get started I'm going to grab the
所以在开始之前，我要抓起
rectangle tool and I'm going to click
矩形工具，然后我将单击
and drag on my canvas to draw a
并在我的画布上拖动以绘制
rectangle like that
像这样的长方形
and I'm going to take this rounded
我要把这个四舍五入
handle over here and bring this all the
把这个拿过来，把这些都拿过来
way down so that we have rounded ends so
向下，所以我们有圆形的末端，所以
that we have this pill like shape
我们有这种药丸状的形状
and then I'm going to convert that to a
然后我将把它转换成一个
path by going to path and selecting
路径：转到路径并选择
object to path
对象到路径
so what I will do now is I will come
所以我现在要做的就是我会来
over here to my meshes tool you can
在这里到我的网格工具，你可以
locate it over here in the toolbar I'm
在工具栏中找到它，我是
going to click on that
我要点击它
and the way this tool works is it allows
这个工具的工作方式是它允许
you to assign colors to an object based
您可以将颜色指定给基于
on a grid of coordinate points and
在坐标点的网格上，
there's two different ways that you can
有两种不同的方法可以
do this you have regular mesh gradients
这样做，你有规则的网格渐变
and then you have conical gradients and
然后你有圆锥形渐变和
you can apply it to the fill or you can
您可以将其应用于填充，也可以
apply to the stroke so I'm going to show
应用到笔划上，所以我将显示
you how to use both of these starting
您如何同时使用这两个起点
off with the regular mesh gradient
禁用规则网格渐变
so if you notice up here in the tool
所以如果你注意到在这个工具上
settings you'll see we have two
设置您会看到我们有两个
different settings here we have rows and
这里有不同的设置，我们有行和
columns
列
I'm going to start off with just two
我将从两个方面开始
rows and two columns so if yours doesn't
两行两列，如果你的没有
say two and two just manually type in
比方说2和2只需手动输入
two and two and then take your cursor
二和二，然后拿起你的光标
and click and drag over your object like
然后在对象上单击并拖动，如下所示
that and you'll see that we now have a
这样您就会看到我们现在有了一个
grid of coordinate points placed over
放置在其上的坐标点的网格
the object
该对象
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
我要做的是我要
click and drag over all of those
在所有这些选项上单击并拖动
coordinate points and I'm going to
坐标点和我要做的
change their color to something like
将它们的颜色更改为类似于
pink down here you could choose whatever
粉色在这里，你可以选择任何东西
color you'd like just choose a mid-tone
你想要的颜色只要选择一个中间色调即可
nothing too light or too dark
不能太亮或太暗
and what I'm going to do now is I'm
我现在要做的是
going to press escape to deselect those
要按Esc键来取消选择那些
nodes and I'm going to click on this
节点，我要点击这个
node right here I'm just going to bring
就在这里，我要带上
this towards the edge of the rectangle
这个朝向矩形的边缘
right there and I'm going to take these
就在那里，我要拿着这些
handles and just straighten them out
把手，然后把它们弄直
like that or rather round them so that
像这样，或者更确切地说，把它们围起来
they they go along the Contour of this
他们沿着这个轮廓线走
object here and you may have to take
在这里反对，你可能不得不带上
these handles and move them up a little
把这些把手往上移一点
bit to accommodate that spacing
位以适应该间距
and I'm just going to adjust these
我只是要调整一下这些
handles so that we have the edge of this
手柄，这样我们就有了它的边缘
mesh going around the Contour of the
网格绕过轮廓
object
对象
a little more smoothly
更顺畅一点
I'll take this handle move this out a
我要拿着这个把手，把这个搬出去
little more
再多一点
I'll adjust this one down a little bit
我要把这个稍微调低一点。
and again we want a nice smooth Contour
再说一次，我们想要一个流畅的轮廓
there it doesn't have to be perfect
在那里，它不一定要完美
you're probably not going to get it
你可能不会得到它
perfect but close enough is good enough
完美但足够接近就足够好了
there like that and I'll do the same
就像那样，我也会这样做
thing with this node here I want these I
关于这个节点，我想要这些我
want my mesh to nicely hug the Contour
希望我的网眼能很好地拥抱轮廓线
of my object so I'm going to adjust all
所以我要调整所有
of these handles here until I have that
在我拿到这些把手之前
result
结果
and then I'm going to come over here to
然后我要到这里来
this side and do the same thing I'll
在这边，做同样的事情，我会
move this one out a little bit
把这个往外移一点
I'm going to move this I'm going to move
我要移动这个，我要移动
this node in close to the edge and I'll
这个节点靠近边缘，我将
take these handles and just move them
拿着这些把手，动一下就行了
out like that
就这样出去了
and once you've done that I'm going to
一旦你这么做了，我就会
take this node here in the center and
把这个节点放在中间，
I'm going to bring this down like this
我要像这样把它降下来
and then I'm going to use these handles
然后我要用这些把手
over here to make it so that this line
在这里制作，这样这条线就可以
kind of like dips down kind of kind of
有点像是往下沉，有点像
sort of like follows the Contour of the
在某种程度上，遵循着
shape here I'll do this with both sides
形状在这里，我会两边都做这个
as well I want to bring this down like
我也想把这件事做得更好
that
那
and now what we can do is we can click
现在我们能做的就是点击
on each of these coordinate points and
在这些坐标点的每一个上
change their colors so if I click on
更改它们的颜色，这样如果我点击
this coordinate point right here
这个坐标点就在这里
I can hold shift and click on this
我可以按住Shift键并单击此按钮
coordinate point over here as well I
这里的坐标点也是我
have them both selected now and then I'm
让他们两个都被选中，然后我
going to hold shift and click on this
按住Shift键并单击此按钮
coordinate point over here and now I
这里的坐标点，现在我
have all three of those coordinate
将这三个坐标都设置为
points selected and I'm going to change
选择了点，我要更改
the color here just by darkening it a
这里的颜色只是把它变暗了
little bit and you can see we end up
一点点，你就会看到我们最终
with the result like that
结果是这样的
and then I'll do the same thing down
然后我会做同样的事情
here I'll select these coordinate points
在这里，我将选择这些坐标点
by holding shift and clicking on them
通过按住Shift键并单击它们
and I'll make these ones even darker
我会把这些弄得更黑
so you can see the result we're getting
所以你可以看到我们正在得到的结果
here it kind of looks like a 3D pill now
现在它看起来有点像3D药丸
if you notice we have a little bit of a
如果你注意到我们有一点
little bit of color error here so I'm
这里有一点颜色误差，所以我
going to click on this handle right here
我要点击这里的手柄
and I'm going to bring this handle up
我要把这个把手举起来
just to adjust this a little bit just to
只是稍微调整一下，只是为了
make this a little more smooth
把这个弄得更顺滑一点
there we go you may have to bring it up
我们走吧，你可能得把它提出来
a little bit
有一点
and I would recommend coming up here to
我建议你到这里来
the smoothing and changing this from
将其平滑和更改为
Koontz to bicubic and that'll make
昆茨到双三次，这将使
things just look even more smooth
事情看起来更顺利了
so now we have dark we have a darker
所以现在我们有了黑暗我们有了一个更黑暗的
gradient here on the bottom I'm going to
在底部的渐变，我要
put a lighter gradient up top here so
在上面放一个较浅的渐变，这样
I'm going to double click this line
我要双击这条线
right here
就在这里
and that's going to allow us to create a
这将使我们能够创建一个
new line there let me actually undo that
那里的新台词让我真的撤销了它
I'm going to press Ctrl Z to undo that
我要按Ctrl Z键来撤消该操作
I'm going to put that a little lower
我要把这个放低一点
there we go and I'll bring this handle
好了，我把这个把手拿来
and move this up
把这个往上移
I'll take this handle and bring it down
我拿着这个把手，把它拿下来
and I'm going to click on this node
我要点击这个节点
right here and I'm going to move this
就在这里，我要把这个
handle so that the Contour is going up
手柄，使轮廓向上
now like that and I'll do the same thing
现在就像这样，我也会做同样的事情
over here on this side I'll bring this
在这边，我会把这个拿过来
up like that
像这样站起来
and now I will click on this node right
现在我将右键点击这个节点
here and I will make this white and you
在这里，我会让它变白，而你
can see the effect there now it kind of
我现在可以看到那里的效果，它有点
looks like a 3D pill now if you want to
如果你想的话现在看起来像3D药丸
add even more in here you can you can
你可以在这里添加更多你可以
add more points to this grid so I'm
向这个网格添加更多的点数，这样我就
going to double click the line over here
我要在这里双击这条线
and now we have another point to work
现在我们有了另一个要点要做
with I'm going to click on that one and
我要点击这一点，然后
I'm going to make this one white
我要把这个改成白色的
and then I'll do the same thing over
然后我会重新做同样的事情
here I'll click on this one or double
在这里，我将点击这个或两个
click on this one and make that white
点击这个，把那个变成白色
there we go and if I zoom out and go to
我们开始了，如果我缩小并转到
my selection tool you can see what we've
我的选择工具，你可以看到我们有什么
done there we've used the mesh gradient
完成后，我们使用了网格渐变
to create this 3D pill looking shape
创建此3D药丸外观形状的步骤
so that's how the mesh gradient Works
这就是网格渐变的工作方式
let's have a look at the conical
让我们来看看圆锥体
gradient now
立即渐变
now let's have a look at how to use
现在让我们来看看如何使用
conical gradients I'm going to grab my
圆锥梯度，我要抓起我的
circles and Ellipsis tool over here for
圆圈和省略号工具在这里
this demonstration we're going to create
我们将创建这个演示
a CD so I'm going to click and drag to
一张CD，所以我要点击并拖动到
create a circle I'm going to hold the
创建一个圆圈，我要拿着
control key so we have a perfectly round
方向键控制，让我们有一个完美的回合
circle like that
像这样围成圈
and let me grab my selection tool and
让我拿起我的选择工具
move this towards the center of the page
把这个移到页面中央
and zoom on zoom in on it a little bit
再放大一点再放大一点
I'm going to come back over here to my
我要回到我的
meshes tool and now I'm going to come up
网格工具，现在我要上来了
here and select this option that says
在此选择此选项，该选项显示
create conical gradient and this works
创建圆锥体渐变，这是可行的
similarly to the regular mesh instead of
类似于规则网格，而不是
putting it on a rectangular grid though
把它放在一个矩形网格上
it wraps it around a circle
它把它包裹在一个圆圈里
so to show you what I mean I'm going to
所以为了向你们展示我的意思，我要
change the rows and columns this time I
这次将行和列更改为
want one row and I want 20 columns 20 is
我想要一排，我想要20列
the maximum value for either of these
这两项中任一项的最大值
input boxes here so I'm going to go with
这里的输入框，所以我将使用
1 and 20 and now I'm going to click and
1和20，现在我要点击并
drag like that and you can see we now
像这样拖动，你就能看到我们现在
have these nodes going in the direction
将这些节点指向以下方向
of a circle rather than on a rectangular
圆形的，而不是矩形的
grid
网格
so let me select all of these and I'm
所以让我选择所有这些，我是
going to change their color to 30 gray
将它们的颜色更改为30灰色
you can access that by coming down here
你可以通过来到这里来访问它
to the color bar and hovering your
到颜色栏并将您的鼠标悬停
cursor over the colors if you notice
如果您注意到了，请将光标放在颜色上
right here it says 30 gray I'm going to
就在这里，上面写着30灰色我要
choose that one
选那个吧。
and now all of these are 20 gray and now
现在所有这些都是20%的灰色
I'm going to press the Escape key to
我要按Esc键来
deselect them
取消选择它们
and now I'm going to zoom in over here
现在我要把这里放大
I'm looking at the top Center Line right
我正看着右上角的中线
here I'm going to double click this part
在这里，我要双击这部分
of the line right here right between
就在这条线的中间
these two lines to add a new line in
这两行中添加新行
here just like that and I'll come over
就在这里，我会过来的
here and add a new line on this side as
在这里，并在这一侧添加新行，如下所示
well I'll double click that line
好的，我会双击那条线
and then I'm going to come down here and
然后我会来到这里，
do the same thing to the bottom side I'm
对底部做同样的事情，我是
going to starting off with the center
从中锋开始
line as a reference move over here to
将行作为参考移动到此处
the left and put a new line in here and
左边放一条新的线在这里
then I'll come over to the right side
那我就走到右边去
and do the same thing
做同样的事情
and now what I'm going to do is I'm
现在我要做的是
going to click on this line right here
点击这里的这条线
now when you click on the line you're
现在，当你点击这条线时，你就是
going to select it's going to select the
选择它就是选择
entire area right there and I'm going to
整个区域都在那里，我要
hold shift and I'm going to click on
按住Shift键，我将单击
this line to select that as well and now
这一行也选择那个，现在
I have both of those lines selected and
我已经选择了这两行，并且
I'm going to change their color to
我要把它们的颜色改成
Yellow
黄色
and I'm going to make this a lighter
我要把这个做得更轻
shade of yellow over here
这里是黄色的阴影
and now I'm going to select the lines
现在我要选择这些线
next to it so I'm going to come over
在它旁边，所以我要过来
here and click on this line right here
点击这里，点击这里这条线
to the left and then I'll hold shift and
向左，然后我会按住Shift键
click on this line right here to the
单击此处的这条线即可转到
right
正确的
and then I'll come down here and do the
然后我会到这里来做
same thing I'm going to hold shift click
与我要按住Shift键单击的内容相同
on this line right here
就在这条线上
to select it and you'll know it's
选择它，你就会知道它是
selected when you see that node
当您看到该节点时选择
highlighted and then I'll hold shift and
突出显示，然后按住Shift键并
click on this line as well now one thing
也点击这条线，现在有一件事
I want to point out when you're doing
我想指出的是，当你在做
this is to make sure that you're
这是为了确保你是
selecting your line you're going to
选择您要选择的线路
hover your cursor over the line and when
将光标悬停在线条上，并在
it's directly placed over the line
它直接放在这条线上
you'll notice that a plus symbol
您会注意到一个加号
populates on the cursor letting you know
在光标上填充，让您知道
that it's active now make sure you see
它现在处于活动状态，请确保您看到
that plus symbol because if it's not
那个加号是因为如果它不是
there and you accidentally click you're
在那里，你不小心点击了你
going to deselect the object and you're
要取消选择该对象，您将
going to have to start all over again
将不得不从头再来
with your selection so I'm going to hold
你的选择，所以我要拿着
shift and click on that and now I have
按住Shift键并单击它，现在我有
all four of those lines selected I'm
所有四行都被选中了我是
going to change their color to Pink
将它们的颜色更改为粉色
and I'm going to bring down
我要把它带到
the lightness of that as well so that we
它的轻盈也让我们
end up with something like that right
最终会有这样的事情发生
there
那里
and now I'm going to do the same thing
现在我要做同样的事情
again over here I'm going to select this
再来一次，我要选择这个
line out here
在这里排队
hold shift select this line over here
按住Shift键选择此处的这条线
and then come down here and do the same
然后来到这里，做同样的事情
thing on this side select this line
这边的东西选这条线
and then this line
然后是这行
and these ones I'm going to make cyan
这些我要做青色的
and again I'll use a lighter shade here
再一次，我会在这里用一个较浅的色调
and now I want to make it look like the
现在我想让它看起来像
disc is reflecting a glare of light so
圆盘反射一道耀眼的光
I'm going to select this line right here
我要在这里选择这条线
and then hold shift and select this line
然后按住Shift键并选择此行
over here on the other side and I will
在那边的另一边，我会
make those ones white so that it looks
把那些画成白色，这样看起来
like it's a little glare of light
就像是一道小小的强光
so you can see what we have here it's
所以你可以看到我们这里有什么
starting to look like a CD
开始看起来像一张CD
so now that we have that in place I'm
现在我们已经准备好了，我要
going to create another object on top of
要在的顶部创建另一个对象
this and apply a mesh gradient to that
这个应用网格渐变到那个
as well so let me grab my selection tool
让我拿起我的选择工具
click on the object and then right click
单击对象，然后单击鼠标右键
it and go to duplicate and I'm just
然后去复制，我只是
going to change the color of the entire
将更改整个
object I'm just going to make that white
反对，我只想把它变成白色
just to clear that mesh that was
只是为了清理那张网格
previously on there
前情提要
and now I'm going to go back to my
现在我要回到我的
meshes tool and now I'm going to use the
网格工具，现在我将使用
opposite values instead of one row and
相反的值，而不是一行
20 columns I'm going to use 20 rows and
20列我将使用20行和
one column
一栏
and now I'm going to click and drag like
现在我要点击并拖动，就像
that and now we have our conical
现在我们有了圆锥曲线
gradient going in circles as opposed to
渐变是绕圈的，与之相反
lines
线条
so let me select all of these nodes here
让我在这里选择所有这些节点
and remove their color by clicking on
并通过点击移除它们的颜色
the Red X down here
下面的红色X
and now what I want to do is let me
现在我想做的是让我
press escape to deselect them I want to
按Esc键取消选择我想要的对象
select each node here
在此处选择每个节点
I want to select every other node going
我想选择每隔一段时间
up this vertical plane right here so I
就在这个垂直平面上，所以我
selected this node I'm going to hold
选择了我要保留的这个节点
shift I'm going to skip this node and
我要跳过这个节点，
I'm going to select the next one and I'm
我要选下一个，我是
just going to repeat that going all the
我要从头到尾重复一遍
way up I'm going to select every other
在这条路上，我会选择每一条
node while holding shift so that I have
节点，同时按住Shift键，这样我就可以
them all selected
都被选中了
and once you've done that you can fill
一旦你这样做了，你就可以填满
them in with white and now we have that
他们穿着白色的衣服，现在我们有了
sort of effect right there and I'm going
就在那里，我要去
to come down here to the bottom and do
来到这里，来到最底层，做
the same thing I'll select this node and
同样，我将选择此节点并
again every other node going down this
同样，每个其他节点都会沿着这个方向运行
vertical plane
垂直平面
and then finally I want to make these
最后，我想做这些
areas if you notice the gradient sort of
如果你注意到渐变排序的话
ends right here this right hand side is
在这里结束这个右手边是
the end point of the gradient so I want
渐变的终点，所以我想
to make these areas white as well I'm
为了让这些区域也变白，我是
going to select these lines right here
我要在这里选择这些行
I'm going to click on the line itself as
我将单击线本身，如下所示
opposed to just the node and I'm going
而不是仅仅是节点，我要
to hold shift and go through here and
按住Shift键穿过这里
select each of the lines as well and
同时选择每一行，然后
again not just the node but the entire
同样，不仅是节点，而且是整个
line we want the whole segment selected
行，我们希望选择整个段
and then I will make those white
然后我会把它们变成白色
just like that and now I'm going to grab
就像这样，现在我要抓住
my selection tool I'm going to change
我要改变我的选择工具
the blend mode of this object I'm going
我要使用的这个对象的混合模式
to come over here to my fill and stroke
来到这里，尽情地抚摸着
menu if you see over here where it says
菜单，如果你看到这里上面写着
blend mode just click on that and change
混合模式只需点击并更改
this to color burn
这是要烧色的
and now we have that effect right there
现在我们就在那里产生了这种效果
so I'm going to bring down the opacity
所以我要降低不透明度
of this a little bit we don't want that
这一点，我们不想要那个
to be too prominent I'm going to bring
太突出了，我要带上
that down a little bit
稍微往下一点
and now I'm going to create some more
现在我要创造更多
circles to place on top of here so it
把圆圈放在这里上面，这样它就
looks more like a CD so let me grab my
看起来更像是一张CD，所以让我拿起我的
circles and ellipses tool let me click
圆圈和省略号工具让我点击
and drag to create another Circle
并拖动以创建另一个圆
I'm holding control while I do that to
当我这样做的时候，我控制着
lock the aspect ratio and let me bring
锁定纵横比，让我带上
the opacity of this up and let me make
这是不透明的，让我来做
this a darker shade of gray something
这是一种深灰色的东西
like 60 percent
比如60%
and I'll place this directly over the
我会把这个直接放在
center of the circle here I'm going to
这个圆圈的中心，我要去
hold shift and select both of these and
按住Shift键并同时选择和
I'm going to Center them up vertically
我要把它们垂直居中
and horizontally make sure you have
在水平方向上确保你有
relative two make sure you have that to
两个亲戚，确保你有那个
last selected and again if you don't
最后一次选择，如果未选择，则再次选择
have your outline distribute menu active
激活大纲分发菜单
you can open it by going to object and
您可以通过转到对象并打开它来打开它
selecting a line and distribute which is
选择一条线并将其分配给
down here at the bottom of the list
在这张名单的底端
and once that's centered let me deselect
一旦居中，让我取消选择
it I'm going to take just this object
如果我只拿这件物品
right here and I'm going to hold Ctrl
就在这里，我要按住Ctrl键
and shift and just scale this down like
然后移动，就像这样缩小规模
that
那
and I'm going to change the blend mode
我要更改混合模式
of this one as well let me come back
也让我回来吧
over here to my fill and stroke menu I'm
在这里我的填充物和笔划菜单我是
going to change the Blends mode to I
将混合模式更改为i
think this one is multiply there we go
我觉得这张照片是成倍的，我们走吧
yeah now we have multiply and let me
是的，现在我们有了乘法，让我
duplicate this again I'm going to right
再复制一次，我要把它做对
click this and go to duplicate I'll make
点击此按钮，然后转到复制我将制作
this one white
这件是白色的
and I'll change the blend mode of this
我会改变这个的混合模式
back to normal
恢复正常
and I'll just scale this down like that
我就像这样缩小规模
and now it looks sort of like a compact
现在它看起来有点像一辆小型车
disc and you can change you can adjust
光盘，你可以改变，你可以调整
the size of these circles if you want
如果你想知道这些圆圈的大小
I'm just eyeballing this here I don't
我只是在看这个，我不是
know if this accurately represents the
知道这是否准确地代表了
proportions of a CD but that looks close
CD的比例，但看起来很接近
enough and then finally I'll put one
够了，最后我会放一个
more circle behind the disk sort of like
圆盘后面更多的圆圈，有点像
as a bevel so I'll take this one here
作为一个斜面，所以我要拿这个
I'll right click it go to duplicate
我将右键单击它，转到复制
I'll make this one a lighter shade of
我会把这件做得更浅一点
gray maybe 20 percent
灰色的可能是20%
I'll scale this up
我会把它放大的
send it all the way to the back by
把它一直送到后面去
clicking this button up here that says
点击这里的按钮，上面写着
lower to the bottom
降到最低
and I'll just resize this accordingly
我会相应地调整它的大小
I'll make that a little smaller
我会把它改小一点。
and I'll maybe even make that a little
我甚至可能会让它变得有点
darker just so it stands out a little
更暗一点，这样它就会稍微突出一点
more
更多
and there you go we have used conical
这就对了，我们用圆锥体
gradients to create that CD design
创建CD设计的渐变
so that is how you can work with mesh
这就是您使用网格的方式
gradients and conical gradients in
渐变和圆锥形渐变
inkscape
墨迹
found this lesson useful then consider
觉得这一课很有用，然后考虑
checking out my inkscape master class
查看我的Inkscape大师课
it's a collection of over 60 videos
这是60多个视频的集合
where I go over all of the tools and
在那里我检查了所有的工具和
features in inkscape and I explain what
Inkscape中的功能，我将向您解释
they are and demonstrate how they work
它们是并演示了它们的工作方式
kind of like how I did in this video we
有点像我在这段视频中所做的
even have a private Community where you
甚至拥有一个私人社区，在那里你可以
can ask questions and get help from me
可以问我问题并得到我的帮助
anytime you want and best of all there's
任何你想要的时间，最好的是有
no monthly membership fees you just pay
你只需支付月费就可以了
17 one time and you're in for Life I'll
17一次，你就会被判终身监禁
have some information about that down
我有一些关于这方面的信息
below if you want to check that out as
如果您想要将其查看为
always thanks for watching
永远感谢您的收看
[Music]
[音乐]
thank you
谢谢